# **Dennis Drueck** — Software Engineer

Naperville, IL GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn (872) 228-5265 denwa.dev@gmail.com

#### About

With 5 years of software engineering experience and 18 years in IT overall, I can readily excel in any environment. My diverse background spans multinational corporations like Tesla and E. & J. Gallo, as well as start-ups and freelancing.

I've resolved numerous complex problems, prioritizing scalability and client experience. Most recently, I created solutions to guarantee stability for critical microservice interactions using Node.js and NestJS, circumventing hundreds of hours of maintenance.

I'm dedicated to continuous growth and am constantly looking for fresh obstacles to overcome.

# **Skills**

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, SQL, Terraform, Bash, Java, SCSS, CSS, HTML

Frameworks: Node.is, NestJS, React.is, Redux, Spring Boot, Express.is, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Cloud SQL, BigQuery, RDS

Tools: GCP, AWS, Jira, GitHub, Concourse Cl, Docker, Kubernetes, Jira, Postman,

Chrome DevTools, Figma, VS Code, DataGrip

Topics: Agile, CI/CD, Job Processing, Socket, HTTP, REST API, Event-Driven, Microservice,

Unit Testing, Performance Testing, TLS, SSH, DNS, Performance Optimization,

Multithreading, Concurrency, PubSub, Messaging

# **Experience**

#### Software Engineer, Tempus Labs via Egen

2023-Present

Environment: PostgreSQL, TypeScript, React.js, Node.js, CSS3, HTML5, Git, GitHub, Jira, Concourse CI, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), Cloud SQL

- Increased release velocity and impact by recognizing the most valuable features and compelling stakeholders to minimize scope creep.
- Streamlined event processing between circular systems, eliminating costly delays and increasing data integrity and system stability in complex microservice architecture.
- Accelerated team skills growth and delivery speed through effective mentorship and constructive, tactful feedback.
- Resolved large amorphous problems by breaking them into manageable components, including safe delivery and release management.
- Resolved resource contention for complex inter-service graphs with semaphore and mutex patterns.

- Conducted Root Cause Analysis (RCA) using various tools including VS Code debugger,
  Splunk, GCP Console, DataGrip, and Chrome DevTools.
- Provided expertise in design patterns for CI/CD and containerization using multi-step builds in Concourse CI.
- Ensured compliance with application development and cloud security best practices, safeguarding patient and organization data privacy and PHI compliance.

#### Full-Stack Developer, Self-Employed

2021-2023

- Provide end-to-end solutions, including full-stack development, UI and UX design, SEO, market research, and digital media, using an Agile approach to build web applications.
- Release products on time by identifying highest value features after evaluating problem statements and distilling requirements in collaboration with product teams.
- Increase traffic and revenue for clients, achieving top SERP rankings and enhancing user experience through excellent page speed, accessibility, and responsiveness.
- Deliver features rapidly, iterating with Agile sprints.
- Improve stability with nearly instantaneous version updates by implementing CI/CD pipelines using Git and GitHub to easily deploy new production builds in seconds.

# Full-Stack Developer (Contract), Martial Arts Technologies | Link

2022-2023

Environment: PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Laravel, Blade, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bitbucket, Jira, cPanel, AWS Elastic Beanstalk

- Contributed to SaaS products for event management in collaboration with the CTO and the product manager to improve functionality and implement time-saving automation.
- Reduced support requests for cross-platform issues by implementing responsiveness and input validation for 50+ web pages using PHP, Blade, jQuery, and Bootstrap.
- Increased SERP ranking and page speed via network and asset optimization strategies.
- Automated time consuming tasks related to logo color extraction by scraping CDNs and analyzing images with JavaScript, Node.js, color-thief and tinycolor2.

## Full-Stack Developer (Contract), TrapMonkie.io | Link

2021-2022

Environment: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Redux Thunk, Node.js, Webpack, Jest, SCSS, Git, GitHub, Cloudflare Pages, Ethereum

- Created and maintained a single-page application to facilitate blockchain transactions in collaboration with the product manager and 1 additional developer.
- Delivered MVP in 1 week, and 2 major updates within 1 week of requirements approval.
- Imported real-time data and performed asynchronous transactions via Ethereum's JSON RPC API using web3.js, providing error-proofing and ease-of-access.
- Optimized cross-platform user-experiences with responsive and adaptive design, lazy-loading, and asset optimization.

Environment: JavaScript, Python, Bootstrap, Selenium, CSS3, HTML5

- Owned development, deployment, support, technical client relations, and in-house training related to all SaaS widgets deployed to 200+ auto dealership websites.
- Delivered exceptional user experiences, overhauling widget assets using JavaScript,
  HTML, CSS and Bootstrap, focusing on unifying visual identity with host sites.
- Reduced time-to-delivery by 50% by restructuring cross-company deployment pipelines.
- Enhanced client-experience with proactive communication and well-prepared proposals, backed by my expertise in HTML and CSS, as well as analytics and market research.
- Conserved 40 hours per month by automating toilsome tasks with Python and Selenium.

#### Education

#### FastTrack Developer Program, Cook Systems | Certificate

2022-2023

- Studied design patterns and developed full-stack applications using Git, GitHub, Java,
  Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, CSS, and HTML.
- Met all deadlines and fulfilled client requirements while leading a team of 3 developers.
- Built multiple full-stack applications through 1-week sprints in Agile teams.
- Ensured version stability by reviewing, testing, and merging git branch pull requests.

# Project: Twitter Clone API | GitHub

Environment: Java, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Maven, Spring Web, Lombok, MapStruct, JPA, JDBC, Postman, Git, GitHub

- Created a REST API web service with Java Spring, including 30 HTTP endpoints to CRUD data related to accounts, tweets, hashtags, likes, follows, replies, and reposts.
- Implemented services, data models, repositories, and controllers using Spring Boot and JPA, including data validation, error handling, and reusable functions.

# Project: Spotify Artist Guessing Game | Link | GitHub

Environment: JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, React Router, Material UI, howler.js, Lodash, Git, GitHub

- Developed a stateful browser game, allowing users to play songs and guess the artist by fetching genres, artists, and songs from Spotify Web API.
- Implemented capability to play again with fresh data by creating configurable components and routes using React.js, Material UI, and React Router.
- Resolved edge cases for smaller genres through caching and query retries, manipulating and persisting data with HTML Web Storage and JavaScript.
- Enabled users to easily play and switch between songs with a single click by utilizing howler.js and React.js Hooks to control .mp3 playback and global volume.

#### Project: Company Management Portal | GitHub

Environment: Java, Spring Boot, Maven, Spring Web, Lombok, MapStruct, JPA, JDBC, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, React Router, Postman, Git, GitHub

- Built a full-stack application that allows users to edit employees, announcements, teams, and projects using React.js, Java Spring, JPA, JDBC, and PostgreSQL.
- Clarified client expectations to ensure all features aligned with the customer's needs, creating distinct objectives for developers.
- Provided the front-end team with ample time to deliver a polished interface, distributing tasks effectively to finish 17 REST API web service HTTP endpoints in under 24 hours.

#### Bachelor of Fine Arts, University of Illinois Chicago

2012

Studied web design, design thinking, visual communication and perception theory.

# **Certifications**

## **FreeCodeCamp.org** | Certificates

2021-2022

Each below certification included 300 hours of coursework and 5 certification projects.

- Back-End and APIs Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js
- Relational Databases PostgreSQL, Bash
- Front-End Libraries React.js, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap
- JavaScript Data Structures and Algorithms
- Python Scientific Computing
- Responsive Web Design Semantic HTML5, CSS3

Additional work history and references are available upon request.